Daniel Hanks Jr

204 Kingsdown Drive - Liverpool, NY 13088

315-944-7574 | dphanksjr@gmail.com

https://dphanksjr.github.io/main

SUMMARY

Experienced IT professional with a broad knowledge of hardware, software, and networking technologies. Proficient in database design and development, software design, programming and debugging. Experienced in teaching classes and training a variety of people in various settings. Data Science experience extracting and analyzing data, turning it into useful information and then visualizing it.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming: Python (scikit-learn, numpy, scipy, pandas, biopython), R, ASP.NET, C++, C#, HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, JSON, XML, XSLT
- Software: RStudio, Visual Studio, Jupyter, SQL Server, MySQL, SharePoint, Microsoft Office, Adobe Creative Suite, VMware, Virtual Box, GIT, IIS, Apache, Tomcat
- Operating Systems: CentOS, Ubuntu, Debian, Windows 2000/XP/Vista/7,8, Windows 2000/2003/2008 Server, OS X
- Networking: Active Directory, Novell, Citrix, LAN, WAN, TCP/IP, WINS, DHCP, DNS, Cisco IOS, VLAN, Routing Protocols (OSPF, EIGRP, IGRP, RIP), ACL implementation, VPNs

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Syracuse University Libraries, Syracuse NY

2/2014 - Present

IT Analyst/Programmer

- Planned, customized, developed, designed and tested library web applications in LAMP environment.
- Imported, exported and retrieved data from various sources for storage and display.
- Installed, evaluated, implemented, and customized open source web software.
- Created system and software documentation as needed for new and existing systems
- Recommend changes to existing systems and implement new systems as needed.
- Reviewed requests for system modifications and analyzed the complexity, scope, and feasibility of implementing the changes.

Bryant & Stratton College, Liverpool, NY

Syracuse, NY

5/2010 -3/2014 9/2016-12/2017

Part-time Evening Adjunct Instructor in Networking Technology

Responsible for teaching students in a hands-on computer lab environment that prepares them for A+, Network+, Cisco and Microsoft certifications. Examples of skills taught to them include:

- Installing, configuring, troubleshooting, and securing networks.
- Managing users and sharing resources.
- Working with network and routing protocols.
- Researching, evaluating, recommending and specifying hardware and software components and complete systems for enterprise needs.

Loretto, Syracuse, NY

10/2012-2/2014

Analyst/Programmer

- Analyzed user requests to determine parameters of required program and if a new program must be created or if an existing program can be modified.
- Designed, coded, tested, maintained and documented complex programs based on user requests.
- Built complex user interface applications and back-end databases using various web development tools, programming languages and scripting languages.

- Prepared user and technical documentation for implementation and support.
- Analyzed and documented user information needs or business problems and determined most effective/efficient programming solutions.

Falk College of Sport & Human Dynamics, Syracuse NY

3/2006 - 10/2012

Computer Consultant

- Designed, programmed and supported college website using ASP.NET, C# and JavaScript.
- Created and updated sites for student groups.
- Built forms that would gather recruiting information and assist in scheduling classes.
- Created master pages to speed up development of web site.
- Wrote and modified databases that utilized SQL.
- Organized and instructed group training sessions on a variety of applications.
- Administered Microsoft Windows Servers (Active Directory), Novell Servers and Microsoft Workstations

Bryant & Stratton College, Liverpool, NY

4/2001 -3/2006

Technology Coordinator

- Setup and managed Windows2003/XP, Novell NetWare and Peer-to-Peer networks
- Implemented Active Directory and Citrix environment for college
- Lead group training sessions on various software applications with faculty and staff
- Developed and implemented backup recovery systems using programs such as ArcServelT and Norton Ghost Enterprise
- Established and maintained network users and security
- Loaded and updated application software such as Oracle Applications, Office 2003/XP, and virus scan software
- Managed inventory of hardware and software, including licensees

CC Plus, N. Syracuse, NY

8/1999 - 4/2001

Computer Consultant

- Designed, created and modified web pages using HTML, Java, PHP, MySQL and programs such as Macromedia Flash, Adobe Photoshop and Dreamweaver
- Created databases and applications in Access and Visual Basic that utilized SQL
- Setup web servers and RAS servers using Windows 2000/NT and IIS 4.0/5.0
- Installed and configured routers and firewalls

EDUCATION

Syracuse University –School of Information Studies

CAS in Data Science, 2017

Bellevue University

MS-Management of Information Systems, 2010 -Information Security Concentration

CERTIFICATIONS

Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA) (Expired 2014) Security + (Expired 2014)